{"name": "72C  2014-6", "questions": [{"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "1. The monthly fees for single rooms at 5 colleges are $370, $310, $380, $340, and $310, respectively. What is the mean of these monthly fees ?", "choices": {"A": "$310", "B": "$340", "C": "$342", "D": "$350", "E": "$380"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "2. Disregarding sales tax, how much will you save when you buy a $12.00 compact disc that is on sale for 25% off ?", "choices": {"A": "$0.30", "B": "$0.48", "C": "$3.00", "D": "$5.00", "E": "$9.00"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "3. Given f = cd3, f = 450, and d = 10, what is c?", "choices": {"A": "0.45", "B": "4.5", "C": "15", "D": "45", "E": "150"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "4. Jorge\u2019s current hourly wage for working at Denti Smiles is $12.00. Jorge was told that at the beginning of next month, his new hourly wage will be an increase of 6% of his current hourly wage. What will be Jorge\u2019s new hourly wage?", "choices": {"A": "$12.06", "B": "$12.60", "C": "$12.72", "D": "$18.00", "E": "$19.20"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "5. The first term is 1 in the geometric sequence 1, -3, 9, -27,\n\u2026. What is the SEVENTH term of the geometric sequence?", "choices": {"A": "-243", "B": "-30", "C": "81", "D": "189", "E": "729"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "6. If  and b = 36, a = ?", "choices": {"A": "6", "B": "18", "C": "72", "D": "324", "E": "1,296"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "7. The shipping rate for customers of Ship Quick consists of a fee per box and a price per pound for each box. The table below gives the fee and the price per pound for customers shipping boxes of various weights. Gregg wants Ship Quick to ship 1 box that weighs 15 pounds. What is the shipping rate for this box?", "choices": {"A": "$ 9.75", "B": "$16.50", "C": "$19.75", "D": "$20.00", "E": "$24.50"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "8. The table below shows the number of cars Jing sold each month last year. What is the median of the data in the table?", "choices": {"A": "13", "B": "16", "C": "19", "D": "20.5", "E": "23.5"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "9. Students studying motion observed a cart rolling at a constant rate along a straight line. The table below gives the distance, d feet, the cart was from a reference point at 1-second intervals from t = 0 seconds to t = 5 seconds. Which of the following equations represents this relationship between d and t ?", "choices": {"A": "d = t + 14", "B": "d = 6t + 8", "C": "d = 6t + 14", "D": "d = 14t + 6", "E": "d = 34t"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "10. If  , then x = ?", "choices": {"A": "3", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "0", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "11. The absolute value of which of the following numbers is the greatest?", "choices": {"A": "-0.4", "B": "-0.042", "C": "-0.0048", "D": "0.04", "E": "0.047"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "12. In the figure below, C is the intersection of AD and BE. If it can be determined, what is the measure of \u2220BAC ?", "choices": {"A": "80\u00b0", "B": "100\u00b0", "C": "110\u00b0", "D": "115\u00b0", "E": "Cannot be determined from the given information\n "}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "13. This month, Kami sold 70 figurines in 2 sizes. The large figurines sold for $12 each, and the small figurines sold for $8 each. The amount of money he received from the sales of the large figurines was equal to the amount of money he received from the sales of the small figurines. How many large figurines did Kami sell this month?", "choices": {"A": "20", "B": "28", "C": "35", "D": "42", "E": "50"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "14. Given that ,  = ?", "choices": {"A": "-50", "B": "24", "C": "36", "D": "50", "E": "72"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "15. Antwan drew the circle graph below describing his time spent at school in 1 day. His teacher said that the numbers of hours listed were correct, but that the central angle measures for the sectors were not correct. What should be the central angle measure for the Core subjects sector?", "choices": {"A": "72\u00b0", "B": "80\u00b0", "C": "160\u00b0", "D": "200\u00b0", "E": "288\u00b0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "16. The area of a rectangular sheet of paper is 32 square inches. The length of the sheet of paper is twice its width. What is the perimeter, in inches, of the sheet of paper?", "choices": {"A": "4", "B": "8", "C": "12", "D": "16", "E": "24"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "17. A car accelerated from 88 feet per second (fps) to 220 fps in exactly 3 seconds. Assuming the acceleration was constant, what was the car\u2019s acceleration, in feet per second, from 88 fps to 220 fps ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "44", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "18. In scientific notation, 670,000,000 + 700,000,000 = ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "19. In a plane, the distinct lines  and  intersect at A, where A is between C and D. The measure of \u2220BAC is 47\u00b0. What is the measure of \u2220BAD ?", "choices": {"A": "43\u00b0", "B": "47\u00b0", "C": "94\u00b0", "D": "133\u00b0", "E": "137\u00b0"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "20. Which of the following expressions is equivalent to  ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "21. Whenever 4x + 7 = 2x - g, which of the following expressions must be equal to x ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "22. For trapezoid ABCD shown below, AB || DC , the measures of the interior angles are distinct, and the measure of \u2220D is x\u00b0. What is the degree measure of \u2220A in terms of x ?", "choices": {"A": "(180 - x)\u00b0", "B": "(180 - 0.5x)\u00b0", "C": " (180 + 0.5x)\u00b0", "D": "(180 + x)\u00b0", "E": "x\u00b0"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "23. Which of the following expressions is equivalent to  ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "24. Sara and Behzad are saving to make a down payment on a house. With an initial deposit of $8,000, they have opened an account that compounds interest at an annual rate of 2.1%. Assuming that Sara and Behzad make no additional deposits or withdrawals, which of the following expressions gives the dollar value of the account 4 years after the initial deposit? (Note: For an account with an initial deposit of P dollars that compounds interest at an annual rate of r%, the value of the account t years after the initial deposit is dollars)", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "25. Right triangle \u25b3RST has its right angle at vertex S. The length of ST is 6.0 feet and the length of RS is 2.5 feet. Which of the following values is closest to the length, in feet, of RT ?", "choices": {"A": "3.5", "B": "4.3", "C": "5.5", "D": "6.5", "E": "8.5"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "26. An artist makes a profit of () dollars from selling p paintings. What is the fewest number of paintings the artist can sell to make a profit of at least $60,000 ?", "choices": {"A": "100", "B": "150", "C": "200", "D": "300", "E": "600"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "27. Last month, Lucie had total expenditures of $900. The pie chart below breaks down these expenditures by category. The category in which Lucie\u2019s expenditures were greatest is what percent of her total expenditures, to the nearest 1% ?", "choices": {"A": "24%", "B": "28%", "C": "32%", "D": "34%", "E": "39%"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "28. When the system of inequalities below is graphed in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane, one of the following graphs is that of the solution set of the system. Which graph ?                        ", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "29. Janelle is loading a truck by using a ramp, as shown below. The ramp is 8 feet long, and the end of the ramp that is resting on the truck is 2.5 feet above the level ground. Which of the following expressions gives the angle of inclination of the ramp?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "30. What is the perimeter, in inches, of the isosceles right triangle shown below, whose hypotenuse is inches long?", "choices": {"A": "8", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "16", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "31. The equation y = ax\u00b2 + bx + c is graphed in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below for real values of a, b, and c. When y = 0, which of the following best describes the solutions for x ?", "choices": {"A": "2 distinct positive real solutions", "B": "2 distinct negative real solutions", "C": "1 positive real solution and 1 negative real solution", "D": "2 real solutions that are not distinct", "E": "2 distinct solutions that are not real"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "32. The radius of the base of the right circular cone shown below is 5 inches, and the height of the cone is 7 inches. Solving which of the following equations gives the measure, \u03b8, of the angle formed by a slant height of the cone and a radius?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "33. A formula to estimate the monthly payment, p dollars, on a short-term loan is                              where a dollars is the amount of the loan, r is the annual interest rate expressed as a decimal, and y years is the length of the loan. When a is multiplied by 2, what is the effect on p ?", "choices": {"A": "p is divided by 6", "B": "p is divided by 2", "C": "p does not change", "D": "p is multiplied by 2", "E": "p is multiplied by 4"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "34. To make a 750-piece jigsaw puzzle more challenging, a puzzle company includes 5 extra pieces in the box along with the 750 pieces, and those 5 extra pieces do not fit anywhere in the puzzle. If you buy such a puzzle box, break the seal on the box, and immediately select 1 piece at random, what is the probability that it will be 1 of the extra pieces?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "35. The length of a rectangle is 3 inches more than twice the width of the rectangle. The perimeter of the rectangle is 36 inches. What is the width of the rectangle, in inches?", "choices": {"A": "4", "B": "5", "C": "9", "D": "11", "E": "13"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "36. The solid shown below is composed of a right circular cylinder and a right circular cone with base diameters and heights given in centimeters. The cylinder and the cone have equal base diameters. What is the volume, in cubic centimeters, of the solid?(Note: The volume of a right circular cylinder with base radius r and height h is \u03c0r\u00b2h. The volume of a right circular cone with base radius r and height h is .", "choices": {"A": "72\u03c0", "B": "96\u03c0", "C": "108\u03c0", "D": "144\u03c0", "E": "360\u03c0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "37. Use the following information to answer questions 37-39.Gianna is converting a 12-foot-by-15-foot room in her house to a craft room. Gianna will install tile herself but will have CC Installations build and install the cabinets. The scale drawing shown below displays the location of the cabinets in the craft room (0.25 inch represents 2 feet). Cabinets will be installed along one of the 12-foot walls from floor to ceiling, and 4 cabinets that are each 3 feet tall will be installed in the middle of the room. These are the only cabinets that will be installed, and each of them will be 2 feet wide and 2 feet deep. CC Installations has given Gianna an estimate of $2,150.00 for building and installing the cabinets.37. A 15-foot wall is how many inches long in the scale drawing?", "choices": {"A": "1.5", "B": "1.875", "C": "3", "D": "3.375", "E": "3.75"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "38. Use the following information to answer questions 37-39.Gianna is converting a 12-foot-by-15-foot room in her house to a craft room. Gianna will install tile herself but will have CC Installations build and install the cabinets. The scale drawing shown below displays the location of the cabinets in the craft room (0.25 inch represents 2 feet). Cabinets will be installed along one of the 12-foot walls from floor to ceiling, and 4 cabinets that are each 3 feet tall will be installed in the middle of the room. These are the only cabinets that will be installed, and each of them will be 2 feet wide and 2 feet deep. CC Installations has given Gianna an estimate of $2,150.00 for building and installing the cabinets.38. Gianna will install tile on the portion of the floor that will NOT be covered by cabinets. What is the area, in square feet, of the portion of the floor that will NOT be covered by cabinets?", "choices": {"A": "72", "B": "90", "C": "140", "D": "156", "E": "164"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "39. Use the following information to answer questions 37-39.Gianna is converting a 12-foot-by-15-foot room in her house to a craft room. Gianna will install tile herself but will have CC Installations build and install the cabinets. The scale drawing shown below displays the location of the cabinets in the craft room (0.25 inch represents 2 feet). Cabinets will be installed along one of the 12-foot walls from floor to ceiling, and 4 cabinets that are each 3 feet tall will be installed in the middle of the room. These are the only cabinets that will be installed, and each of them will be 2 feet wide and 2 feet deep. CC Installations has given Gianna an estimate of $2,150.00 for building and installing the cabinets.39. CC Installations\u2019 estimate consists of a $650.00 charge for labor, plus a fixed charge per cabinet. The labor charge and the charge per cabinet remain the same for any number of cabinets built and installed. CC Installations would give Gianna what estimate if the craft room were to have twice as many cabinets as Gianna is planning to have?", "choices": {"A": "$2,800.00", "B": "$3,000.00", "C": "$3,450.00", "D": "$3,650.00", "E": "$4,300.00"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "40. Use the following information to answer question 40-42Trapezoid ABCD is graphed in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below.40. What is the slop of CD ?", "choices": {"A": "-3", "B": "-1", "C": "1", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "41. Use the following information to answer question 40-42Trapezoid ABCD is graphed in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below.41. When ABCD is reflected over the y-axis A'B'C'D\u2019, what are the coordinates of D' ?", "choices": {"A": "(-12, 1)", "B": "(-12, -1)", "C": "( 12, -1)", "D": "(1, 12)", "E": "(1, -12)"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "42. Use the following information to answer question 40-42Trapezoid ABCD is graphed in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below.42. Which of the following vertical lines cuts ABCD into 2 trapezoids with equal areas?", "choices": {"A": "x = 2.5", "B": "x = 3.5", "C": "x = 4.5", "D": "x = 5.5", "E": "x = 6.5"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "43. Given that for some real number a, what is x + z ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "26", "D": "27", "E": "48"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "44. The points E(6,4) and F(14,12) lie in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane shown below. Point D lies on EF between E and F such that the length of EF is 4 times the length of DE. What are the coordinates\nof D ?", "choices": {"A": "( 7, 5)", "B": "( 8, 6)", "C": "( 8, 8)", "D": "(10, 8)", "E": "(12, 10)"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "45. A certain triangle has a perimeter of x meters. One side of the triangle is 60 meters long, another side is  the length of the perimeter, and the third side is  the length of the perimeter. What is the perimeter, in meters, of the triangle?", "choices": {"A": "15", "B": "35", "C": "84", "D": "95", "E": "144"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "46. The difference (larger minus smaller) between 2 numbers is 15. If n represents the larger number, which expression below represents the average (arithmetic mean) of the 2 numbers?", "choices": {"A": "7.5", "B": "n + 7.5", "C": "n + 15", "D": "n - 15", "E": "n - 7.5"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "47.  = ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "48. A square in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane has vertices at (1, 3), (2, 1), (4, 2), and (3, 4). Where do the diagonals of the square intersect?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "(2, 3)", "C": "(2, )", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "49. The shaded region in the graph below represents the solution set to which of the following systems of inequalities?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "50. In the standard (x, y) coordinate plane, line a contains the points (-4, 2) and (-1, -3), and line b contains the points (3, 0) and (7, 0). At what point does line a intersect line b ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "51. In the figure below, the side lengths and the length of an altitude of parallelogram BCDE are given in feet. What is the area, in square feet, of BCDE ?", "choices": {"A": "25", "B": "38", "C": "48", "D": "66", "E": "88"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "52. The square below is divided into 3 rows of equal area. In the top row, the region labeled A has the same area as the region labeled B. In the middle row, the 3 regions have equal areas. In the bottom row, the 4 regions have equal areas. What fraction of the square\u2019s area is in a region labeled A ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "53. Which of the following is a quadratic equation that has  as its only solution?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "54. Bonkosi mixes 60 milliliters of Solution A with 40 milliliters of Solution X. Solution A has a 40% hydrochloric acid concentration; Solution X has an unknown hydrochloric acid concentration. When Bonkosi tests the resulting 100-milliliter solution, she finds that it has a 36% hydrochloric acid concentration. What is the hydrochloric acid concentration of Solution X ?", "choices": {"A": "19%", "B": "24%", "C": "30%", "D": "32%", "E": "38%"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "55. What are the real number values of x that make the equation  true?", "choices": {"A": "All real numbers", "B": "x &lt; 0", "C": "x &gt; 0", "D": "x \u2264 0", "E": "x \u2265 0"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "56. The functions y = sin x and y = sin(x+a) + b, for constants a and b, are graphed in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below. The functions have the same maximum value. One of the following statements about the values of a and b is true. Which statement is it?", "choices": {"A": "a &lt; 0 and b=0", "B": "a &lt; 0 and b &gt; 0", "C": "a = 0 and b &gt; 0", "D": "a &gt; 0 and b &lt; 0", "E": "a &gt; 0 and b &gt; 0"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "57. Which of the following number line graphs shows the solution set to the inequality |x - 5| &lt; -1 ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "58. The sides of an acute triangle measure 14cm, 18 cm, and 20 cm, respectively. Which of the following equations, when solved for , gives the measure of the smallest angle of the triangle ?(Note: For any triangle with sides of length a, b, c that are opposite angles A, B, C, respectively.  and )", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "59. For all values of x where the expression is defined, ", "choices": {"A": "-3", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "60. Mr. Martin wants to plant 7 trees evenly spaced along a straight fence 300 feet long, with 1 of the trees at each end of the fence. About how many feet apart should he plant the trees?", "choices": {"A": "33", "B": "38", "C": "43", "D": "50", "E": "60"}, "correct": "D"}]}